truenorthlogic.com 2016-11-23

# Privacy Policy - Performance Matters

## **PERFORMANCE MATTERS  PRIVACY POLICY**

### **Personal Information Protection Partnership**

Performance Matters (“Performance Matters” or “we”) partners with School Districts (“Districts”) to protect all student and teacher personally identifiable information (“PII” or “information”).  We recognize the importance of privacy to our website visitors and users of our online services (collectively, “you”).  The Performance Matters platforms enable Districts to regulate who is given an account to access student and teacher information.  Performance Matters does not sell or use PII for marketing purposes.  We use strong security protection on all information while it is transmitted and stored, and we employ security practices and monitoring to ensure the confidentiality and integrity of your information.

In order to provide you with the best possible experience it may be necessary for us to collect and store certain information about you.  This Privacy Policy explains what types of information we may collect and how we use that information to operate our public website (“Public Website”) and subscription online services (“Subscription Services”) and provide products and services to you.  We do not retain personal information longer than is required to provide the Subscribed Services.

We will not make material changes to this privacy policy without first providing notice to Districts, allowing them to make changes prior to using personal information in any manner inconsistent with the terms that they were initially provided.

This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to our _Terms of Use_ which can be found here: <http://www2.performancematters.com/terms>

**Access to sections below:**  
Children’s Online Privacy Protection

Information We Collect

Use of Information

How We Share Your Information

Public Posts

Information Security

Links to Other Websites

Updates and Questions

### Children’s Online Privacy Protection

We do not permit children under the age of thirteen (13) to register for the Subscription Services directly.

In the event we become aware that a child has contributed unsolicited personal information to the Public Website through online message boards, electronic feedback mechanisms or other means, Performance Matters will promptly delete such personal information from its systems.

We support requests for access to and correction of student PII by the student or their parent or guardian, in accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act (“FERPA”).

If you are a parent or guardian and you believe your child has registered for the Subscription Services or otherwise supplied personal information to us without your consent, please let us know by sending an email to [legal@performancematters.com](mailto:legal@performancematters.com) and we will take the appropriate action.

### Information We Collect

_Personally Identifiable Information –_ When you use our Subscription Services or our Public Website, PII is submitted to us by you or your District on your behalf. We understand the confidentiality of your personal information, and only use that information to provide the specified Student Services.

_Behavioral Information –_ When you use our Public Website and our Subscription Services, we may collect information about your network connection, browser, pages viewed, number of clicks, and other information. 

We use “cookies” to automatically gather some of this information. A cookie is a small text file that we send to your computer to collect information about your activities on the Public Website and our Subscription Services.  The cookie transmits this information back to the Public Website and our Subscription Services each time your browser requests a page, and the information is stored to help facilitate your use of the Public Website the next time you visit.

_Advertising_ – We do not display any third party advertisements on our Public Website or in our Subscription Services.  We also do not sell or provide access to any personal information to any third party advertisers.

### Use of Information

We use PII in our Subscription Services to provide virtual educational services to you and your District and to improve our services.

We use PII in our Public Website to inform you of our products and services.

We may monitor IP addresses and other behavioral information for security purposes, site administration, trend analysis, to prevent fraud, troubleshoot problems, and to otherwise improve our services in both the Public Website and in our Subscription Services.

We typically do not link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable. This means that a visitor’s session will be logged, but the visitor remains anonymous to us.

We do not sell any information we collect from you, including PII and behavioral information, to any third party.  We may share aggregate, numeric-level information with third parties for educational research purposes.  We have procedures in place to de-identify (anonymize) all personal information prior to disclosing it for research purposes, in accordance with FERPA and other law.

We may engage third party agents to perform certain functions necessary to provide our services to you.  These agents may have access to PII needed to perform their functions.  However, these agents may not use your PII for their own purposes, such as sending you marketing offers about their products or services.  

We may make an application programming interface (“API”) available to third party service providers for their use in providing services that complement our programs (such as online content supplementing our offerings).  Some standard program information, such as course information and enrollment dates may be disclosed to such third parties in connection with the API.  All third parties receiving personally identifiable information as part of their service are required to adhere to all applicable privacy laws and regulations.

We may disclose to third parties aggregated, anonymous information regarding traffic analysis and other information regarding the sites.  This information will not include PII about you. We use “Google Analytics” to improve our Public Website and Subscription Services. Google Analytics collects information about frequency of usage, page visits and related data.  Google Analytics collects only IP addresses not names or other identifying information of our visitors.  You can learn more about how Google Analytics operates by reviewing Google’s privacy policies, available at <https://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>.

Please be aware that in the event our company or any of its assets are ever sold, the information we have collected may be transferred to the new owner.  In addition, your personal information may be transferred to third parties without notice to you in order to comply with applicable law, law enforcement agencies, to protect our rights, or protect the rights of other users.

### Public Posts

Performance Matters’ corporate Public Website may feature forums, message boards or other media which enable you to submit content.  Please remember that any information you disclose in these areas is public and you should exercise caution to avoid disclosing any personal or otherwise sensitive information.

### Information Security

We have employed administrative, technical, electronic and contractual security measures to protect the information described in this policy from intentional or unintentional use or disclosure.  Though we will take these steps to safeguard your information, we cannot eliminate all security and privacy risks inherent in Internet use.  You acknowledge awareness of and accept such risks, including the limitations of security and authentication measures and the chance that any information transferred via the Public Website or our Subscription Services may be susceptible to eavesdropping, hacking and other security hazards or misappropriation.  We take all commercially reasonable measures to prevent or mitigate damages of any kind associated with these security risks.

### Links to Other Websites

The Public Website or our Subscription Services may contain links to other websites.  We cannot guarantee your privacy once you leave our sites and we are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of any websites to which the sites may link.  We are not responsible for the content of external websites.  We encourage you to consult the privacy policy of any other website you visit.

### Updates and Questions

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or your personal information, or wish to correct, update or remove any personal information you have provided to us, please contact us at [legal@performancematters.com.](mailto:legal@performancematters.com)
